

SEATTLE, WA
www.hasstimh.com
hasstimh@gmail.com
www.linkedin.com/in/tim-h-hass
206.920.2777

As a Web Developer, I incorporate my experience with systems to deliver innovative solutions for end users. I'm fascinated by the creative process. It's truly magical to create something from nothing, to use words and symbols to bring people's ideas to life. I enjoy learning and problem solving, and want to use my talents to impact people's lives in a positive way.

SKILLS

HTML5+CSS3+Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, React, Redux, Node, Express, Django, Postgres, MongoDB

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

PROJECTS

EIE.io Garden App, Backyard Garden Activity Tracker - (Postgres/Express/Node)

- Deployed on Heroku, learned about the Sequelize ORM (models and migrations), auth, axios and APIs **TaskMaster**, Project Management App MERN STACK (Mongo/Express/React+Redux/Node)
- Used GitHub workflow for this group project, responsible for models/db, projects filter and react-router **TBEY**, eCommerce site prototype (Postgres/Django/Python)
 - Deployed on Heroku, used context-processors to provide user cart experience.

EDMONDS COMMUNITY COLLEGE, Lynnwood, WA (June 2010 - Jan 2018)

Learning Management Systems (LMS) Administrator, Canvas by Instructure - (3 years)

- Maintained Javascript and Cascade Style Sheets (CSS) college branding and DOM manipulation files.
- Integrated and administered Learning Tool Interoperability (LTIs) within LMS environment, such as Panopto, McGraw Hill, EvalutionKit, and other third party solutions.
- Created and problem-solved user account, course and system issues.
- Preformed quarterly system configuration and responded to online course issues.
- Provided online course and end user reporting services.

Student Technology Advice & Resource Team (START) Program Coordinator (4 years)

- Conceived, procured funding for, implemented and managed student help desk that became institutionalized after the initial pilot phase (1 year).
- Maintained budgets, created operational procedures and oversaw development of knowledge base for student body.
- Recruited, trained and mentored student employees and volunteers.
- Partnered with and reported to Student Executive Board, Instructional Leadership, and Information Technology Director on project outcomes.

Business Systems Analyst Intern (1 year)

- Performed Gap Analysis on an in-house application and produced a report on findings.
- Conducted interviews with end users to gather system and user requirements.
- Created system models, business process diagrams, and system requirements documentation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MERCER, Seattle, WA (Oct 1999 - May 2009)

National Subject Matter Expert - Global Property & Administration Department

- Implemented Events Management Software (EMS) Software in multiple offices across the US and Canada, allowing employees access to reserve rooms and resources in remote offices.
- Managed and supported facilities, safety, security, and other real-estate projects both locally and nationally.

US NAVY (June 1991 - Oct 1999)

Gas Turbine Systems Technician (Electrical) 2nd Class/GSE2/E5

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, Seattle, WA (Jan 2018 - April 2018)

Web Development Immersive

EDMONDS COMMUNITY COLLEGE, Lynnwood, WA (Aug 2009 - May 2012)

Computer Information Systems - Associate of Technical Arts: Web Application Developer & Database Information Technologies Business Systems Analyst Certification

US NAVY

Gas Turbine Systems Jet Propulsion Electronics "A" School (Aug 1991 - Sept 1992)